[Pilot] Begumpet Tower, this is Deccan Air 582.
Minimum fuel, requesting
landing clearance.
[ATC Operator] Turn back Deccan Air 582.
I repeat, turn back Deccan Air 582.
Unable to go around.
We have a fuel emergency,
goddammit!
[ATC Operator] Turn back, Deccan Air 582.
There's something wrong.
I'm out of fuel!
Why won't you let me land?
[Pilot] Begumpet Tower,
requesting reason for denial!
[ATC Operator] You are not cleared to land,
Deccan Air 582.
Why won't they let us land?
Che! Che!
Che do you copy?
Vir, what's happening?
Why won't they let me land?
How much fuel is left?
Six minutes.
I can do one more landing.
Divert the plane to Air Force station
Hakimpet Airfield, N1733 E07831.
Switch to company frequency now,
go, go go!
What? Are you nuts?
Just land, bugger!
I'll deal with the rest!
Roger that!
[music crescendoes]
Hey, stop!
[suspenseful music playing]
[music picks up]
Che, can you hear me?
Che! Come in Che!
Are you on course?
Can you hear me?
Hakimpet airstrip 1-5, in sight.
Hakimpet tower, this is Deccan Air 582...
Do you read us?
This is Captain Chaitanya Rao,
Batch of 1987, Ex-Airforce.
Please acknowledge.
[ATC Operator] Deccan Air 582,
this is Hakimpet tower.
This is restricted airspace.
You're not permitted to land here,
turn around immediately.
This is an order!
Parade, Close Order March!
Vir!
[drums playing]
- Che, can you hear us?
- Stop them!
Che!
[men screaming]
Che, come in, Che!
Che, can you hear me?
Che!
[inspirational music playing]
Che, can you hear me?
[inspirational music continues]
[man grunting]
[soldiers giving orders]
[guns cocking]
[music crescendoes]
[train horn blaring]
Hey!
Eating meat right after
a temple visit!
[baby crying]
Dad, how do you know
if it bothers God?
Let her hog as much
as she wants now.
If she starts stuffing her face there,
she'll be rejected again!
Well, it'll be their loss!
Your brother has spoilt her!
Of course she'll be rejected.
The boy has already declined...
And she's still going
all the way to meet him!
That's precisely why I want to meet him.
What?
He said he doesn't want to
come pick a girl like cattle!
That's why I'm going to see him.
Of course he'll say that!
He won't say that he's
unemployed and broke, will he?
Look, I did a background check.
He's a lot older than you.
Besides, he was thrown out
of the Air Force.
He's totally jobless.
Dad, am I getting married or you?
- Chill out!
- Oh God!
It's tough being the father
of a modern girl!
We were better off not sending
these girls to school, brother!
[man screams]
Serves you right!
[Passenger] I am dead!
My dear girl.
[Female passenger] Help him up.
Be careful.
Come sit.
- Keep your hands off me!
- I was helping, you ungrateful brute!
You've turned this reserved coach
into a fish-market!
Hey mister, stop whining!
We'll get off at Jarandeshwar.
Then you can stretch
your legs and sleep!
Jarandeshwar?
You've boarded the wrong train!
This train goes straight to Satara.
It's been a year...
Now this train makes
a daily stop at Jarandeshwar.
This boy from our village -
He sat peacefully in protest
on the railway tracks
until the railway authorities
met our demand!
Soon, you can have
the train to yourself.
We'll be flying in an aeroplane!
And who's going to make you fly?
Our boy, Vir!
[music starts playing]
- Let's go.
- Our stop has arrived.
With your head held high
Flow like the ocean
Don't fret about the little things
Gotta maintain that attitude
I've got nerves of steel,
ain't no one in my vicinity
The hero of my story
Is me, only me
This world is an illusion
A boat against the crashing waves
Don't think too hard
Dance while you have the chance
This world is an illusion
A boat against the crashing waves
Don't think too hard
Dance while you have the chance
Whatever the wise ol' man said
Is right, my boy
Why make a hue and cry
Take a chill pill
and take a nap
Don't let the fun times stop
Someday we'll vanish into thin air
All smoke and mirrors,
eyes foggy with delusion
This world is an illusion
A boat against the crashing waves
Put all your worries aside
Dance while you have the chance
The guy dancing in the black kurta,
that's Vir.
- Dancing at a funeral procession?
- He was Vir's friend...
With friends like these,
who needs enemies?
What a bloody weirdo!
You really want to marry this guy?
Raju had told us that
he didn't want a depressing funeral.
He wanted a rollicking farewell.
What are you doing?
The girl's family are here to meet you!
Come on, dance!
Move your body!
[music continues playing]
Come on, let's go!
Hold on, stop!
Stop, stop!
[man groans]
He lives under the
shade of a mountain.
This land is parched...
Yes, it's very large...
And your daughter will own it!
He says it's parched,
you say it's large...
Who do we listen to?
Brother!
Our land may be barren,
but our hearts aren't.
Ah! Hear that?
Please come.
Come on get off.
Let's go.
Now let's look at this palace.
What is all this?
- It's nice, isn't it?
- Yes, it's very nice.
This is our special local delicacy.
Is there no shop around where
one can get cake, buttered buns...
You expect to get cake here?
I wonder if they even have a toilet!
We don't.
Your girl will have to go
into the fields.
Whatever land you see around,
that's all there is.
Zero value. Zilch!
The government took over
our fertile land to build a dam,
and handed us this barren land
in exchange.
But our Vir will turn it green too!
I'm neck-deep in debt.
Any money that comes in,
goes in repaying the debt.
So you have nothing?
[playful music starts]
I have an idea.
Business idea.
What now, Rani? No cake...
Will ideas fill your stomach?
Can't believe we travelled so far
to see this wastrel. Let's go!
Wait.
What's your business idea?
I want to make people fly.
On a bullock cart?
[cow moos]
On aeroplanes.
Cheap airline tickets.
Low-cost Aviation...
Twenty four banks have rejected me so far.
He's just being modest,
his business will take off soon.
We were told he's an Air Force officer,
that's why we came here.
Rani has plenty of suitors-
Twenty boys have rejected me so far.
- There she goes.
- Hey!
I can cook, sew, sing...
[playful music playing]
But I won't do any of that.
I want to start my own bakery.
Feeling light, having
blurted out the truth?
Come, let's eat now.
- Hey Mandar!
- What?
So your friend's gonna fly people
on cheap planes? For real?
Cheap tickets, not cheap planes!
You can sit on an aeroplane too!
And how will you fund
this airline of yours?
Enough! Let your father
do the talking.
It's my life at stake, not his!
What's your problem?
Going on and on...
- Can't you let us talk?
- She's a smart girl!
Let them talk.
Twenty guys rejected you, right?
Twenty four banks rejected you.
Let's talk about that first.
Most people can't handle bold ideas.
Most guys can't handle
bold women either.
How to start an airline
in one, two, three...
Just three steps?
Sounds pretty simple.
Why haven't you done it yet?
Starting a bakery is even simpler.
Why haven't you done it?
I'm waiting for a
'No Objection' certificate.
Really?
That's why.
I know what a bank is.
What's that written underneath?
- Ven-ture...
- Venture Capitalists.
Banks only grant loans
against a collateral.
Venture capitalists invest money
in ideas where they see potential.
The idea is the collateral.
I should find a Venture Capitalist too.
[Vir laughs]
Whose pictures are those,
all over the place?
Is he one of those 'Venture' guys?
No.
Paresh Goswami.
A man from a small village...
who built India's biggest airline.
He's my hero.
He held on to his big dreams,
and flew with them.
Do poor folks who can
barely make ends meet
really need to fly on aeroplanes?
A century ago, the poor
didn't need electricity...
and fifty years ago,
we didn't need motor vehicles!
Why must the rich always decide
what poor folks need?
Can't we decide for ourselves?
Don't we want to progress?
You won't get it, dad.
It's business!
It's a yes from me.
For what?
For marriage.
- Wow, Vir!
- That was quick!
We met just two hours ago.
Are you crazy?
Sometimes, one just knows.
Whether it's ten
minutes or ten years,
my decision won't change.
So why waste time?
That's our Vir!
I want to waste some time.
If I'm investing my life on an idea...
I need to think.
- I'll decide by morning.
- There she goes again!
Hey Mandar...
That's our Rani for you!
Can I have some pickle?
[inspirational music playing]
Let's go.
Move!
[cow moos]
Your mother said you have
a nice house in the village...
With a bathroom,
electricity, and all.
Why did you lie then?
That's not my house.
My father built it.
He's the one who got electricity
to our village too.
He wrote letters to everyone-
from the village head to the Prime Minister.
That's how we finally
got power in the village.
But I did things differently.
Down with the Government!
Down with tyranny!
[train honking]
Down with the Government!
Down with tyranny!
[protestors screaming]
Down with the Government!
Down with tyranny!
[suspenseful music playing]
[train honking]
- Vir, Mandar got hit by a stone!
- Vir!
- Don't worry, Mandar!.
- I can't see!
I can't see anything!
Lift him up.
I can't see anything! Vir!
What happened?
What do you think?
Your son started a riot again!
Not a riot. A protest.
This is hooliganism!
Protest is what Gandhi did!
So what Bhagat Singh did
wasn't protest?
Mandar's head was badly injured.
He nearly lost his sight!
I go around the whole village
advocating non-violence...
And my own son
is busy pelting stones!
Dad, wasn't it you who said
that our village won't progress
until we have train connectivity?
Tell me?
Hey!
Have you no brains at all?
Did we not educate you?
If you want to demand trains,
do it properly, write a petition--
Your hands have worn out
writing letters all your life!
Calm down, now!
Your temper goes out of control
when you're hungry.
Your father's petition
got us electricity.
Or we'd still be using candles- -
Yes, twenty years
after he wrote it!
Twenty years...
What an achievement!
Writing letters doesn't
make you a revolutionary!
Vir! Enough!
- Kaveri, let him speak!
- Yes Ma, let me speak.
We had to travel 100 kilometres
just to get Mandar's wound dressed!
We have no hospital, no trains...
Go, write petitions...
And drown in the pool of
your self-righteousness!
If you want your rights,
you need to raise your voice.
You need to be ready
to risk your life!
There's a difference between
non-violence and cowardice.
And you, Dad - are a coward!
A defeated and jaded coward!
And you'll remain one
all your life!
[thunder rumbling]
Great!
Your 'non-violent' facade
finally gone!
[somber music playing]
Forgive me, my son.
Even after I die...
Don't lay your eyes
on my cowardly face.
Vir, Vir...
Vir!
[music stops playing]
You sure have a temper!
What happened then?
Then what?
I took the exam,
got admitted into the
Short Service Commission...
And then the Air Force.
[upbeat music playing]
I've packed three boxes
of food this time...
Two for Vir, and
one for the postman...
Aunty!
And I've attached a note:
"Have one box if you want,
but leave the rest for my son!"
The last time, all the boxes
were delivered empty!
Aunty, there's a letter from Vir.
Uncle... Vir's letter.
[letter smacks the ground]
Give it to me!
I'll read it myself.
I've studied till the 5th grade,
I don't need anyone's help!
Let him write!
All day he writes notes
cursing my son...
The day I get my hands on them,
I'll burn them all!
[both laughing]
"Ma, how are you?"
"I'm doing great here.
Don't worry about me!"
"I passed the exam..."
"Chaitanya ranked first,
I secured the second rank..."
"And Sam came fourth!"
"I'm Pilot Officer
Vir Jagannath Mhatre now!"
[inspirational music playing]
[inspirational music continues]
Ma...
There's a senior officer here
called Nedumaaran Sir...
He reminds me of a certain
grouchy old schoolteacher!
[upbeat dance music playing]
[dance music continues]
Sir!
Jai Hind, sir!
Vir!
- Yeah, what?
- Vir!
Bro!
[plane taking off]
50 rounds around the parade ground!
50 kilos deadweight!
Take your friends along!
100 rounds, 80 kilos in
one and a half hours.
Move!
[inspirational music playing]
[music intensifies]
Vir!
Mandar, how are you, man!
I'm great! You?
I'm fantastic!
Where's Ma?
Isn't she around?
She's right here, behind me!
Call her quick!
I have only two minutes left!
Aunty, come fast!
- Aunty, quick!
- Hold on! He can't walk fast.
Vir, speak to Aunty.
- Here.
- Hello, Vir?
Your dad is here too.
Speak to him first!
Hello!
Dad! How are you, Dad!
- Hello!
- How are you, Dad!
Dad! Hello!
I hear you, Dad!
I can hear you, keep talking!
I think he hung up...
No Dad... I'm right here!
Dad? I can hear you, Dad!
Why would he want to speak
to a cowardly loser like me?
Please don't say that, Dad!
It's not like that!
Never mind. Let's go.
Hello!
Hello! Hello, Vir!
Vir!
Dad!
[somber music playing]
He won't speak to me.
Careful, Uncle.
Just one more call!
Officer Mhatre!
Sir, just one call.
One call, sir...
It's very important!
- Sir, just one call.
- He can have my call, sir.
No.
Rules are the same for everyone.
Everyone gets three minutes.
Call next month. Move now!
Just one call, sir. One call...
[music intensifies]
Sir!
Why was Nedumaaran
after your life?
Did he throw you
out of the Air Force?
No, he didn't.
I resigned.
To start my own airline.
[Ganesh] I told you we should have
left by the last train!
This girl is a piece of work!
[Sarika] She won't listen to anyone!
What are you doing here?
Come on! Let's go!
Get up. Quick!
- [Kaveri] It's not like that!
- [Ganesh] Not like what?
What were you doing here?
[Kaveri] My boy is not like that.
Come. Let's go inside.
Hey!
[Ganesh] Come on!
You won't stay here another minute!
[music starts playing]
[both scolding]
[playful music playing]
Hey!
You were just chatting, right?
[Mandar laughing]
[wind blowing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[music picks up]
If it's ok with everyone,
I'll get a wedding date fixed.
We'll have a beautiful canopy
right in the center of the marriage hall.
- No.
- What?
Ok, we can have
an outdoor ceremony too!
I don't want to marry him.
The boy has said yes.
Why are you acting pricey now?
When twenty boys rejected me,
did you ask why?
May I ask why?
Because you're already married.
Did you know?
And so am I.
Kickstart your airline.
And I'll work on my bakery.
Once our careers are on track,
we can make a decision.
Till then...
Don't get in touch.
[playful music continues]
The haircut suits you,
by the way.
Rani!
Hey! What kind of matchmaker are you?
All you care about is food!
Couldn't find anyone
other than this arrogant girl?
At this rate, you'll never get married!
Sure I will!
If at his age,
he can find girls like me...
I still have a lot of time!
So you finally met your match!
How does it feel?
Serves you right!
I'm so done with you!
- She's so stubborn!
- She'll never find a husband.
Go, drop them at the station.
Hell, no! Let them walk.
She can marry some milquetoast...
Who she can dip into hot tea!
Go, drop them.
Fine, it's your fuel.
Waste it if you want!
Hey, let's go bakery.
We don't want to be
related to you anyway.
[playful music playing]
I want to take you in my arms
Say whatever is in my heart
Want to dwell in your eyes
Endure all your tantrums
My heart's no longer mine
You've stolen it away
With a wink of your eye
All your wishes
I'll make them come true
The moon and the stars
I'll pluck them all for you
All your wishes
I'll make them come true
- At least take a look at my proposal, sir!
- We're a small micro-financing bank, Vir!
- We can't grant such a big loan!
- Please try, sir!
[music continues playing]
I always knew you're the one
Never before did I
lose my heart to anyone
What's taking you so long,
come be mine
I lost myself in you, and how
My mind, heart and soul,
it's all yours now
I've lost myself to you
All your wishes
I'll make them come true
- I'm Vir Mhatre...
- Sir, I already have many of these.
For your birthday or anniversary,
Your one-stop shop is Rani bakery!
Hear that, Aunty?
Vir only likes cake these days!
The minister is busy right now,
but I will talk to him.
[song continues playing]
- Sir--
- I can't meet you now. I'm late!
I'm here to meet Paresh Goswami.
Sir, you can't meet him
without an appointment.
And you can't get me a slot
for the next ten months, right?
I've been hearing this
for the last ten months!
- Here's my card.
- Sir, I already have a hundred of these.
I've printed thousands.
[music continues playing]
Ok, let me try this out.
No, your logic is wrong.
Override the method of the derived class.
Ok.
I think we got this.
Yes. It's running!
Source code ready!
You should have been
an IIT professor, sir!
- Brilliant!
- Brilliant?
He's living off his father-in-law!
Left his well paying Air Force job,
to sit at home and give tuitions!
Brilliant, my foot!
It's ok.
[horn beeping]
Now, make–
Hey, Mr. Bill Gates...
Richard Branson is here to see you!
Hey Vir!
You'll never find an investor!
What, uncle?
Luring these boys with
the promise of a partnership...
You'll ruin their lives
along with yours!
I can't hear you, uncle!
Oversmart bugger!
Take it from me in writing...
Your airline will never take off!
Do you hear me?
Can't hear you.
We'll talk tomorrow!
Here.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- You're welcome.
Thank you.
Ma'am, here's your boarding pass.
And I'm really sorry, but we allow only
one hand-baggage per passenger.
- Please check-in the rest of your bags.
- Check-in?
They contain pickles and snacks.
It'll all be ruined!
There's a long queue ma'am,
people are waiting.
They're for my sister,
she's pregnant.
- Excuse me, Sir...
- Excuse me! Are you listening?
Do you know what
pregnancy cravings are like?
Can you come to
counter number 4 please?
Have you ever been pregnant?
Hello. Excuse me!
Is your manager a lady?
Call her. She'll understand.
- Call her.
- [Vir] Madam!
I'll take it.
I don't have any luggage.
- Really?
- Yes, don't worry.
Okay, thank you so much.
Now that's a gentleman!
Now check him in quickly.
These are my boxes.
Sir, here's your boarding pass.
- Thank you and have a safe flight!
- Thank you.
- Thank you so much!
- No problem.
You won't run off with my
pickles and snacks, right?
I'll decide once I've tasted them!
- Do you live in Mumbai?
- Yes.
So what are you going to Delhi for?
- I have work there.
- I see. What work?
Are you a journalist?
- How'd you guess?
- Your barrage of questions!
Chitra Musale,
All India Radio, Senior Producer!
I'm Vir Jagannath Mhatre.
- Oh, you're Maharashtrian!
- Yes, ma'am.
- So what takes you to Delhi?
- I have a meeting there.
With whom?
[Vir laughs]
[toilet flushing]
[man humming]
[water running]
Excuse me?
Good evening, sir.
My brother Bhavarlal is waiting outside.
- Just call him in.
- Sure, sir.
Are you okay?
Should I cancel the flight?
Don't fuss. Just an anxiety attack.
Did you have your medicine?
Tell me something...
Do the staff use this washroom too?
That guy just did his business here...
I'll have it cleaned.
I'll have him fired.
[music intensifies]
Paresh Goswami!
Are you kidding me?
I'm going to offer him
a business partnership.
He won't even look at you.
Try getting within ten feet of him.
Wanna bet on it?
Sure.
[Announcer] Business class passengers traveling
from Mumbai to Delhi on flight-
Hey, where are you going?
The announcement was for Business class.
Relax, there's still time for us
'cattle-class' passengers to board.
Look.
A business class ticket?
You spent 20,000 rupees...
Then why were you standing
in the economy queue?
Strange!
I've drained my bank account
for this one hour meeting.
I'll go back by train,
in the general compartment.
Alright, I'll be off.
Mr. Mhatre!
My snacks...
I'll get them with me.
Thank you.
[Attendant] Good evening, sir.
Welcome on board.
Hello.
[Pilot making announcements]
Turboprop deal is through, sir.
Excuse me.
Mr. Goswami.
[announcements continue]
I'll see you sometime soon.
Congratulations on
'Businessman of the Year Award', sir.
It's a proud moment
for the Jaz family.
[seatbelt sign dings]
Hello sir.
Sorry for disturbing you, but I had
no other way of meeting you.
I'll come straight to the point, sir.
I want to start a new airline...
And you're my inspiration, sir.
- Vir Jagannath Mhatre.
- Excuse me.
Sir, this entire row is blocked
for our chairman.
- You want to start an airline?
- Yes sir.
An airline for the common man.
[music intensifies]
Will the common man try to make a living
or fly in the clouds?
Both.
- Sir my--
- Sounds like a charity scheme.
Sir, I want to partner with you
and start a low-cost airline.
India's first low-cost airline, sir.
Every second man on earth thinks
he has the next big innovative idea.
But every innovative idea isn't practical.
Sir, I know your time is very precious.
I won't waste it.
So you're saying you have an idea
to make low-cost aviation profitable
that we haven't thought of yet?
With all due respect, yes sir.
Sir, customers currently buy tickets
only via travel agents...
who charge a hefty 14% commission.
Just like the middlemen between
farmers and consumers.
If we were to eliminate
the middlemen, it will be...
How will passengers book tickets then?
On the Internet, sir. Online booking.
So farmers will harvest internet now!
Sir, people can access the internet
at their local post office.
There are about 500 post-offices
in Maharashtra alone,
all with internet connectivity.
Reliance petrol pumps
also have internet access.
There are 1475 of them
across India, with Internet.
People can book their tickets there.
In a few years, everything from
booking to banking will happen online.
The Internet will be at
everyone's fingertips.
And what about the software
needed to book tickets?
Interworld.
The company that creates software
for all international airlines...
I've spoken to them.
Sir, if you want,
a humble craftsman can fly
with a clothing tycoon.
- If I want to make it happen...
- Yes.
But I don't want that.
[music stops]
My passengers pay for 5-star hospitality.
They don't want to fly with
labourers, porters and fishermen
after paying all that money!
Some birds can't fly,
even with wings.
And some men can walk,
even without a spine.
Excuse me...
I have an airline to run,
my friend.
Take him to Economy.
Sir, do you mind coming with me–
Why the heck should I
go to Economy class?
I've paid your chairman
for Business class.
I have the ticket.
- Sir, please-
- Get your hands off me!
Get your hands off,
or I'll break your teeth!
Hey, get me some coconut water.
[inaudible whispering]
[Pilot] Ladies and Gentlemen, this is
Captain Sharma again from the flight deck.
Unfortunately due to a technical snag,
we have to return to Mumbai.
We apologise for the inconvenience caused.
Our crew will guide you from here on.
Thank you.
The ticket may be yours,
but the plane is mine.
[intense music playing]
This way.
I know my way around!
- Your pickles and snacks.
- Thank you so much.
Mr. Mhatre...
Take care!
Come, drop me outside.
Mr. Mhatre!
I am Prakash Babu.
Venture Capitalist, Fundflow Ventures.
I know.
I've made many rounds of your office.
It's impossible to get even
five minutes of your time.
[Prakash laughing]
Well, thanks to your stunt,
I have an hour to spare now.
Want to chat?
[people chattering]
Sir, your dosa.
Thank you.
Vir, if you want to
get money out of me,
at least buy me lunch
at the 5-star hotel next door!
I'm sorry you couldn't
eat on the flight because of me...
But please, I insist...
Just try this food once, sir.
- It's excellent, actually.
- Excellent?
Brother!
Sir says the food's excellent.
People come all the way
from Chennai to eat here.
Tell him your secret ingredient?
There's no secret.
We get all our cooking supplies
from the Chintamani store nearby.
And guess what?
The 5-star hotel over there
also buys their supplies from there!
And Vir Bhai, don't tell anyone...
But their chef comes here
every night for dinner!
- Enjoy your meal.
- Thank you.
Listen!
Ever had a Dosa at the
5-star hotel next door?
You think I'd be able to
digest a 200 rupee Dosa?
And why would I, when I can have
the same thing here for sixteen bucks...
With unlimited chutney!
Some more chutney, please!
I've got another appointment, Vir...
So enjoy your Dosa...
A 5- star will label this Dosa
'Black gram pancakes with lentil soup'
and sell it to you for 200 bucks.
Here, at a lower cost, it's a win-win
for both customer and seller.
Same ingredients, same quality,
same cleanliness...
Then why such a difference in cost?
Because they have fewer overheads.
My airline too will have
minimum overheads, sir.
Newspaper, meals, water -
ten percent of the ticket cost...
I won't provide any of it.
And I won't charge
flyers for it either.
India's moving at a fast pace, sir.
People just want to go from
one city to another for work.
They don't need meals
on a one hour flight.
We'll reduce the weight on the flight.
There will be no extra food or staff.
Big airlines do two trips a day,
we'll do six!
But how? There are rules, Vir!
According to the rules,
Pilots cannot fly for
more than eight hours a day.
A day has twenty four hours.
Safety checks, cleaning, fueling
for six flights, six times a day.
That would take six hours.
What do we have left?
We still get eighteen hours
of flying time.
If each flight takes two hours,
we can do six trips in twelve hours.
That still leaves us with
six hours of flying time.
Our pilots will fly in three shifts.
Every flight of ours will have
not two, but six pilots.
Sir, humans get tired.
Aircrafts don't.
But... this has never been attempted.
Exactly.
What if I say no?
You'll only be the 21st investor
to call me a crazy fool and shoo me off.
I'll find a 22nd one to pitch to.
Sir, look around you.
Not one seat empty,
not one waiter standing idle.
Our aircraft will be
a flying Udupi restaurant.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Yes.
Sir, the bill.
[Prakash] Vir!
I'm travelling for four months.
[Prakash] When I come back,
pitch this to the Fundflow board.
And if they laugh at me
after hearing your crazy idea...
[Prakash] You'll owe me another Dosa!
Sure, sir! It'll be my pleasure!
Thank you, sir!
[uplifting music playing]
Hey! What?
I'm still eating.
Always in a hurry...
[uplifting music continues]
I need to go to the
village for a few days.
For what?
Vir! Go for it!
Catch it. Let's go.
[uplifting music playing]
[Jagan] Kaveri, we spent our whole
lives on rickety bullock carts...
Let these kids fly!
[uplifting music playing]
[Mandar] Why are you suddenly obsessing
about that witch after three years?
Who knows if she
even stays here anymore!
Hey, stop!
Isn't that her Uncle?
Oh my God!
You're still on a bike!
Where's your airplane?
[Mandar] So your bakery has opened!
Won't you offer us a
sample piece of cake?
Buy what you want!
No freebies here!
Let them have cake, uncle.
Give them some biscuits too.
To dip in hot tea, you know.
Here.
Got married yet?
Yeah, have a kid too. Look.
Hey, give us a smile.
How about you?
- We're here to see a girl.
- With a pipe?
That's why we stopped to buy cake.
- How could we go empty-handed?
- Is she a plumber?
Holy cow!
Three years, and you're
still meeting girls?
What about your airline?
I've found a Venture Capitalist.
Once our meeting happens,
it will take off.
So you're still at the first step!
You know what?
Forget about aeroplanes.
Get an auto-rickshaw!
Zip through the three steps!
Hey Mandar, let's go!
We'll find other bakeries on the way.
- Come on, stop hogging!
- You won't!
There's no other bakery in this area!
Not surprising!
It's a shitty location for a bakery!
If you opened it opposite
a school or college,
there would have been a long queue!
Get it?
Yeah, whatever! Move on!
- Hey, Uncle!
- Move aside!
Let's move, you ass!
- [Rani] Get an auto-rickshaw!
- She's as cocky as ever...
And a liar too!
She has no husband or kids!
How do you know?
Her uncle just gave it away!
Who will marry her anyway?
Let's go.
Come on bro, move!
Whether it's your Birthday
or anniversary...
For every occasion,
there's Rani Bakery!
Milk cake for your girl,
and fruit cake for your mom!
[hooligans jeering]
Eat sweets and talk sweet!
Two cakes for the price of one!
Milk cake for your girl,
Fruitcake for your mum!
Hey Honey-bun!
Why did you lie about
being married with a kid?
Eat sweets and talk sweet!
Buy one and get one free!
Listen Honey-bun!
Look...
You're a weirdo, and so am I.
No one's going to
marry weirdos like us.
Why don't we marry each other?
What do you say?
[hooligans laughing]
Eat cake and make merry!
Come, hurry to Rani Bakery!
Hey, Honey-bun!
Why did it take you three years
to remember this weirdo?
My village land was barren.
It's turning green now.
And my airline should
take off soon too!
Come on, say yes!
And what if your airline fails?
What if your airline fails?
Well, we'll still have Rani Bakery!
It's doing well, right?
Yeah...
Milk cake for your girl,
and fruit cake for your mom!
Hey, Honey-bun! Say something?
I have three conditions.
Oh God, Rani!
He's come all the way...
Number one - I don't want
any squabbling over money.
'Your money, my money'...
Whatever we have, will be ours.
Ok.
Number two - My work is
no less important than yours.
If I'm busy, I'm busy.
Ok.
And number three...
If I start a family with someone,
they'll be the most important to me.
If you put our family in danger,
I'll mix rat poison in your food.
Ok.
Go. Think it over.
I've already decided.
- I won't give you a divorce later!
- I won't ask for one!
- Ok.
- Ok!
Yes, Mhatre!
You snubbed my proposal
three years ago...
What made you say
okay so quickly now?
Sometimes, you just know...
that whether it's ten minutes
or ten years,
your decision won't change.
So why waste time?
Using my line on me, smartypants!
Come one, come all to Rani Bakery!
Meet one weirdo and get one free!
[romantic music playing]
You're such an oddball, you really are
Your mind's all twisted and bizarre
I'm a smart cookie, sweet and tart
Kolhapur's Queen, ruling hearts
I'm so smitten by you, I swear
Get a palanquin and whisk me away
My God!
Gosh, you're such a cheeky lad
Your wicked charm,
Boy, it drives me mad
Gosh, you're such a cheeky lad
Your wicked charm,
Boy, it drives me mad
[music continues playing]
Such an oddball
Craziest of them all
I'm like fire in a forest
I'm like thunder in a storm
I'm like fire in a forest,
come extinguish me
I'm like thunder in a storm,
come roar with me
Why do you stare from a distance?
Like scent in a handkerchief,
I carry you in my thoughts
I'm behind locked doors,
Come pry me open now
My God!
Boy, you're such a cheeky lad
You'll open a new bakery
in Mumbai, right?
Gosh, you're such a cheeky lad
Your wicked charm,
Boy, it drives me mad
No newspapers or meals in the plane.
The more the aircraft weighs,
the more the fuel cost.
By not painting their aircrafts,
American Airlines reduced
their weight by 225 kilos.
225 kilos means, the plane can
accommodate four more passengers.
So you don't like them heavy...
No. I like them light and fiery.
Why do you stand at the shore,
pondering away
My eyes beckon you,
come dive into them
Please come in.
Consider it your own.
I'm yours, hook, line and sinker
Come steal me away
Cast your net, O Fisherman
Trap me in your arms
My God!
Gosh, you're such a cheeky lad
Your wicked charm,
Boy, it drives me mad
Gosh, you're such a cheeky lad
Your wicked charm,
Boy, it drives me mad
[music continues playing]
You're such an oddball,
you really are
Your mind's all twisted and bizarre
You're such an oddball,
you really are
Your mind's all twisted and bizarre
Just like soap or oil,
customers will be able to buy
plane tickets on their own.
Thank you.
That's ok,
but how will this be profitable?
The Government run Hindustan Airlines
is already running losses.
- Worth almost 10 billion, right?
- Yes.
And you want to sell tickets
at half the price of the competition?
But sir,
if you see our pricing structure,
my competition isn't Hindustan Airlines,
but the Indian Railways...
And that's running profits!
A Boeing plane costs 1.36 billion.
- Even if you buy it second-hand...
- 900 million?
900 million.
And you plan to start a whole airline
with a budget of 100 million?
Who says we need to buy planes?
We need to lease them.
We'll rent planes.
Really? Which company will lease out
their planes at this price?
- American Airways!
- American Airways?
After the Twin tower attacks,
their airline business
has suffered big losses.
They're selling their planes
at half the price.
We can take advantage of that
and lease their planes!
And what if our revenue
is less than expected?
We'll have to shut the company!
If all our flights run
even sixty percent full,
we can break even
in six months flat.
The calculations of the proposal
are in front of you.
Please have a look.
But what if we don't even
achieve sixty percent occupancy?
Sir, what's the airfare
from Mumbai to Delhi?
- Twelve thousand.
Average occupancy sixty percent, right?
If other airlines can sell
tickets for twelve thousand rupees
and get sixty percent occupancy,
By selling tickets for six thousand rupees,
we can do better than sixty percent!
You are forgetting one key thing.
People who travel by train
aren't used to buying flight tickets.
- It's a mental hurdle.
- Absolutely.
But sir, more people traveling
will mean more business,
which means more job requirements,
which means even more travelers.
We might have to increase
our flights per day from five to fifty!
Once it becomes a habit,
the average train passenger
will fly more than a frequent flyer.
[inspirational music playing]
After all, who doesn't want to fly?
Okay. We'll get back to you.
Thank you, sir.
[music slows down]
[inaudible discussion]
Sir...
Vir...
I'm really sorry, but...
You don't have to buy me
any more dosas!
Congratulations.
The board has given a unanimous nod.
Thank you sir. Thank you.
There's one issue though...
It's a public limited company,
shareholders' money is involved...
It will take three to six months
for the funds to be released.
Sir, getting the DGCA licence
will take the same amount of time.
That's what I'm really worried about, Vir.
In the meantime, what if
American Airways' rates go up,
Or if someone else gets the same idea?
I'll tell you what...
Book three aircrafts.
By the time you get the licence,
get the painting and stickering
of the aircrafts done in Malaysia.
But to book the aircrafts,
we'll have to pay American Airways
a 4.7 million advance...
Can you raise the money
on your own?
I can get a loan
against my mother's land.
Are you sure?
My mother never says no to me.
Great then.
Go, think of a name for the airline!
Thank you, sir.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
Please, come sir.
Please come in, sir.
You asked me to come at 8:30,
I've been here since 7.
Everyone else has gone in,
when will my turn come?
It's the DGCA office,
not your local tea shop.
Sit down.
Take a seat!
[somber music playing]
How are you, sir?
I was waiting for you...
Lunch break for an hour.
Everyone eat and come back!
Go ahead!
[music speeds up]
Hello! Captain Vir Jagannath Mhatre, sir.
Prakash Babu asked me to meet you!
Hi, yes Mr. Mhatre!
- I saw your proposal. It's interesting.
- Thank you.
But can we do this tomorrow?
I need to leave early today.
Sure, sir.
Everything okay, thank you.
[fast-paced music continues]
Hello, sir!
Did you fix an appointment
with the new Civil Aviation Minister?
[somber music playing]
- Hello, sir.
- Oh! Mr. Vir, right?
Actually, I have an urgent meeting
with the new Civil Aviation Minister.
Tomorrow, for sure!
We'll finish it off.
Sir, the meeting will
happen today, right?
Oh, no!
Mr. Deshmukh's on leave now.
Come back next week.
Why didn't you tell me
this yesterday?
You took three months
just to give me an appointment!
You're his PA,
don't you know his schedule?
I'm just telling you
what I've been asked to say, sir.
Even Mr. Ratan came here,
waited and left.
His airline never started.
Who do you think you are?
I'm bleeding money
every passing day, sir...
Try to understand, please!
Small fry can't swim against sharks.
Go home.
And don't come back.
[somber music playing]
[Kaveri] Vir, we haven't paid the interest
in three months now...
The money-lender has been
coming home everyday.
What should I do?
[Sam] Paying hangar charges in Malaysia
has left us with just 300 thousand!
Are you sure
we'll get the license, Vir?
[Radio] This is All India Radio.
Tomorrow evening,
the Science Fair for Girls
organised by the International
Girl Child Welfare Organisation
will be attended by
President Abdul Kalam
who shall be interacting
with the participants.
The programme will be
broadcast live on All India Radio
tomorrow evening at 5 pm.
And now it's time...
It wasn't a serious bet!
The more stress you take,
the worse it will get. Relax!
What do you mean, relax!
Only media persons are
allowed in here.
If we get caught,
we go straight to jail!
- ID, ma'am.
- Yes, here.
Nothing will happen. Once
the programme is over,
I'll just try to talk to
him for two minutes.
- Oh God!
- What, 'Oh God'?
If my airline takes off,
you'll get free tickets for a lifetime.
For your entire family!
But only domestic flights.
I don't want free tickets.
If they're cheap,
I'll buy them on my own!
I want your first interview.
Exclusive!
And what do you mean,
'if' your airline takes off?
I'm just one sheep in a herd
of 900 million...
But you're a tiger!
That's why I'm risking jail for you.
So no 'if's and 'but's, you have
to make it happen mister!
Here, ma'am.
Sir, bag.
Wait.
Raise your arms.
You can go.
What's in your pocket?
Ok, you can go.
Thank you.
Wait.
Go ahead.
[Student] Good morning, sir.
You came from a village,
and now you're India's President.
What advice would you give us
in order to achieve something?
[A. P. J. Abdul Kalam]
Actually, it's very simple.
All you need is four things.
Only four things.
Number one - Aim!
Focus on your goal,
don't let anything distract you.
Number two - Knowledge.
Gather as much knowledge as you can.
Number three - Hard work.
Number four - Perseverance. Determination.
If you have these four things,
any citizen of this country
can achieve anything they want.
No, sir! There's a fifth thing too!
Excuse me!
Questions from the media
aren't allowed right now.
Which publication are you from?
A chance! Opportunity, sir.
The citizens of our country
need opportunities.
Just those four things aren't enough!
The common man needs
an opportunity to dream.
No matter how hard these kids work,
without opportunities,
they won't get anywhere!
All I want is one chance, sir!
I want to start this country's
first low-cost airline.
I want every common man to
be able to touch the skies!
To at least be able to meet
their dying father one last time!
Sir, please listen to me!
Sir, hear me out, please!
Let me speak to him, please!
[serious music playing]
- Namaste sir.
Sir, my name is Vir Mhatre.
I'm from a village near Jarandeshwar.
My father was a schoolteacher there.
- Vir.
- What happened, Ma?
Your father is very unwell.
The doctors have given up!
Ma, please don't cry.
He's just waiting for you...
He wants to see his son
before he dies.
I swear to God. Go tell Dad,
I'll be there in the morning.
[Vir] Everything will be fine.
Trust me.
Come soon, son!
[Vir] Tell him, Vir will be there.
- [Vir] Please tell him that for me.
- [Kaveri] Please come fast, son!
[sad music playing]
Don't worry man.
Everything will be okay.
Vir!
Vir! Take this.
You can catch the last flight!
- I'll return it once I'm--
- Shut up!
This is only six thousand rupees sir,
the ticket is for 11,200 - business class.
I don't want business,
I want economy.
I'm sorry, sir.
Economy seats are fully booked.
- Excuse me, I am getting late here!
- Yeah, one sec.
Ma'am, my father is seriously unwell.
I have to reach by morning anyhow.
Can you do something for me?
I'm sorry sir, you can't bargain here.
We don't give any discounts.
Please take your money
and step aside.
- Excuse me.
- Yes, yes...
How much- how much time
do I have to buy the ticket?
Five minutes. Sir please, there are
people waiting in the queue!
When is the next flight?
After two days. Sir, try and
understand, please step aside...
There are people waiting,
why don't you understand sir?
Please, sir.
Sir, can you lend me
five thousand two hundred rupees please?
I'll return it to you.
My father is very serious.
Only Business class is available.
I have a little money...
When you fly, you should
bring money, okay?
Sir, can you help me?
I just need 5200 rupees.
I need to go,
my father is very sick, please!
Sorry, mister.
- Is he mad or what?
- I don't know...
[suspenseful music playing]
Excuse me.
It's an emergency,
my father's on his deathbed.
Can anyone loan me
5200 rupees please?
Please, just 5200 rupees.
Papa, please help that man?
- Read your comic!
- Sir, please help me.
I just need 5200.
I'll write down the address
and give it to you.
I'll return it to you.
Please, I beg you, sir!
- No.
- Please!
Ma'am... Ma'am can you help me?
[sad music playing]
I'm a real Air Force officer.
Please, ma'am?
My name is Mhatre, batch of 1987...
Please help me.
I have only two minutes left!
The flight will leave.
Please. I just need 5200 rupees.
Anybody! Anybody please...
I'll give you my home address.
Here, see. This is my father.
He's very sick.
Mhatre House,
Jarandeshwar post...
Pin - 415011...
Here. I promise,
I'll pay the money back.
- Just 5200 rupees!
- Security! What is this?
People are begging
in an airport now!
No, I don't want charity.
I'm asking for a loan.
Just 5200 rupees.
Please try and understand!
Please leave from here.
Security, take him!
- Please, please!
- Hurry up and take him away.
The flight will leave.
My father is very serious!
Please, for my mother's sake!
She's old, she has no one else!
It's very important, please...
Someone help me!
Sir! Sir please try and understand!
[engine stalling]
What happened?
It looks like something is wrong.
I will have to check.
[nostalgic music playing]
You're a coward!
A defeated and jaded coward!
And you'll remain one all your life!
[sad music playing]
[sad music continues]
[inaudible groans]
[music crescendoes]
[Vir] Down with the Government!
Down with the Government!
[Mandar] Vir!
I can't see anything!
Vir!
[sad music continues]
[music fades away]
Vir!
Ma...
Ma, I'm here...
Don't be angry with me...
[Vir sobbing]
I told you, didn't I?
That your father can't die
in peace without seeing you?
His life slipped away while he was
staring at the door!
What could I have done?
The body had started to rot...
We had to cremate him!
Despite having a son,
someone else did his last rites!
Like an unclaimed corpse!
"Vir, Vir, Vir..."
He died crying out your name!
But Vir only cares about his ego!
No! No, Ma...
Why are you here now?
Have you no shame?
[Kaveri sobs]
Look, see what your father thinks of you!
Read!
Take a look!
"Vir left home today."
"I'm sure he'll make it big!"
"He's a fighter, unlike me."
"Vir is right.
I really am a coward."
Read the other one!
"If Vir says he'll make
the villagers fly on a plane,"
"then I'm sure he'll do it!"
"He's a man of his word!"
Your father always said,
time is the most precious thing.
A person who doesn't value time,
can't possibly value relationships!
Dad...
Ma...
[both sobbing]
Ma, I didn't have enough money...
I tried really hard to come soon,
but I couldn't, ma...
Please forgive me...
I wasn't angry with Dad...
I just didn't have money, Ma!
Forgive me!
Dad...
Dad, please forgive me!
It's not what you think, Dad...
I'm still your son...
Please forgive me, Dad!
Since the last three years,
all I've dreamt of day and night...
is to enable every citizen
of this country to fly.
Did we refuse you a licence?
You went straight to the President!
Sir, meeting the President
was easier than meeting you!
Anyway...
[upbeat music playing]
[upbeat music continues playing]
- Mr. Walia!
- Hey, Trivedi!
Your airline Red Magpie is
expanding its flight sectors...
Given the current state of
Indian aviation,
do you think this
is a wise decision?
Aviation Minister Nakul Parekh
has gone on record to say
that the Government won't bail
you out under any circumstances.
If I take a girl out,
I won't just take her
for dinner, will I?
I'll have dessert too!
[reporters laugh]
Risk is the kick, man!
I'll never need a bailout.
What's our brewery business for,
after all?
What's the big deal about this
'Aero show'?
It's just like our village fair!
Only the toys here are a little bigger!
- Will ours be like that one?
- No, like that one.
- Can we see it up close?
- No!
Only VIPs can go there,
those who own the aircrafts.
Our planes are still in Malaysia.
Chaitanya will bring them.
Once they're here,
you can inspect them inside-out!
Hi, Paresh!
Jaz Airways is going to
increase its flights, is it?
You know, I don't take risks...
I'm purchasing Turboprops.
For the Cargo fleet.
That's your man there.
What's happened to
Prakash Babu's business sense?
Partnering with that nut- job...
Master and Disciple -
out to create history!
Oh, is that the stud?
The one who wants to turn
the sky into a roadside market?
He'll fall flat on his face.
Walia, a bumblebee has
tiny wings and a big body.
According to the rules of aerodynamics,
it shouldn't be able to fly.
But it flies. Why?
Because no one told the bee that it can't.
But this insect needs to be told.
[pager beeping]
Chaitanya. "Call me!"
[Che] Vir, American Airways has
canceled our deal!
The Indian DGCA guys are
asking for the plane blueprints!
- Blueprints, why?
- I don't know Vir.
They've never asked any company
for blueprints till date.
Why are they doing this to us?
They said, go ask the Indian DGCA
why they are doing this!
[Che] American Airways is taking
our planes back!
And they've imposed a 5 million fine
on us for blocking their planes!
Why is the Indian government
targeting just us?
- Hey, mister!
- I'll pay, don't worry.
[suspenseful music playing]
You go ahead. I'll manage!
[suspenseful music continues]
What are these new rules, sir?
How can plane manufacturers
share their blueprints?
No company ever reveals
its trade secrets!
This rule is unfair!
We've been slapped with a 5 million fine
because of this rule.
- Please do something, sir!
- That's not my problem.
I can't break the rules
just for you, can I?
But you can instantly make rules
to benefit some people.
You could go to the President again.
Running an airline is
for big shots.
Go back to your village
and ride a bullock cart!
And you continue being
Paresh's little lackey, you scoundrel!
Just because a man is silent,
you think you can walk all over him?
You're assaulting a Government servant!
Here! I'm drowning that servant.
Move! Get out!
[intense music playing]
- Prakash sir!
- Vir! What are you doing here?
Sir, we have a big problem.
DGCA changed their by-laws
at the last moment.
They want the aircraft blueprints!
American Airways has cancelled our deal.
And they've imposed a penalty too!
Sir I need a 5 million advance
from you please.
Or else Deccan Air will crash
even before it has taken off.
6.4738 billion!
No sir, 5 million.
That is the revenue of
Jaz's travel agency.
Per year!
And you went to him with an idea
that would kill all that revenue.
Paresh Goswami rules Indian aviation.
In fact, Paresh Goswami
is Indian aviation.
Everyone is in his pocket.
DGCA, Ministry of Aviation...
and me.
The hidden investor of Fundflow Ventures
is Paresh Goswami.
Prakash.
He only paid attention
to you for ten minutes...
And all your dreams
of flying in the sky
went crashing down into the sewer.
Your life will go by,
just paying off the loan.
Don't invite his attention again.
Look, your aircraft...
[Prakash laughs]
They now belong to Jaz Airways.
[aircraft taking off]
But Vir... Your idea?
Genius!
[sad music playing]
[sad music continues playing]
[music picks up]
Paresh!
Come out!
Where is Paresh?
Where is he?
Paresh!
[intense music playing]
[Vir screaming]
Paresh!
[music fades]
[music intensifies]
[Guards screaming]
[malevolent music playing]
[Vir shouting]
[Vir sobbing]
[malevolent music continues]
I told you not to
marry that madman!
But you just love stressing out
your parents, don't you?
What big talk,
flying planes and all...
And now he sits at home,
living off your earnings!
Does he feel no shame?
Tell the cow to shut up.
Been shouting all morning!
What? You have a cow?
She's calling me one!
Fine, I'll leave! I got you this.
Your husband can't provide
for you anyway.
Take the saree. I don't want it.
Get up, let's go!
Keep the cake.
- Leave it!
- Let's go!
So much attitude,
as if she's married a King!
You could have at least
let me finish my cake.
Haven't you seen a
cake before? Just go!
[wind blowing]
When did you get back?
Our neighbour Firoz Uncle
brought us special pudding for Eid.
Both his daughters are appearing
for the civil services exams this year.
He's really stressed out.
And tuitions are so
expensive these days.
He asked me if you would
be willing to coach them...
And he doesn't want you
to do it for free!
I told him that
I'll ask you and get back.
Didn't take you much time.
For what?
To tell me that I'm a burden on you.
[serious music playing]
Did I say that?
Then say it! Be straightforward!
Your mom's right.
When you're hungry,
your temper goes out of--
Don't coddle me, I'm not a child!
At least your mom straight up
called me a loser and left!
So now you'll vent
that anger on me?
Let's plan our way ahead!
Why don't you plan it!
You're running this house anyway.
Maybe you can tell me
how to start an airline too!
It's not like baking a cupcake.
Throw in some flour, sugar, butter
and you're all set!
For your investors,
your idea's a cupcake too.
And don't forget that this house
is running thanks to those cupcakes!
Are you an idiot?
Tell me?
Only losers wallow in self-pity.
Got it?
[intense music playing]
Then why are you staying
with a loser?
Go! Get lost!
[plane flying in background]
[somber music playing]
[Vir screaming]
[somber music continues]
O lord the fire of love torments me
O lord the pain of
love makes me weep
Give my heart some respite
Only those torn apart
Know the pain of separation is
To live without your lover
Is as good as being dead
When you made me crazy in love
I accepted it as Your will
O Allah, I seek your refuge
O Allah, don't torment my heart
Allah, don't torment my heart
The fire of love torments me
The pain of love makes me weep
Give my heart respite
O God, bring me some relief
[music continues playing]
With your Almighty grace
Show me a way
Don't abandon the heartbroken
O miraculous one
Nothing is beyond you
You can mend broken hearts
Where will I go, Mhatre?
This is my home.
Lovers wandering desperate
Why put love through such a test
Life without love
is as good as death
My anger has cost me a lot.
Dad died with a broken heart.
And now you...
I just shoot my mouth off.
Then don't!
I'll never do it again.
I promise.
I searched for you everywhere!
I would've made you
run around all night...
If I wasn't pregnant.
That's how you tell me this?
Are you crazy?
If I act sane,
would you ever listen?
What are you...
My crazy honeybun!
Give my heart some respite
Hey, Rani!
Rani!
Breakfast is ready downstairs. Come.
Hold on! I'm feeding them.
[sparrows chirping]
These sparrows are so dumb!
They eat so little!
Once the pigeons come,
there will be nothing left for them!
They're tiny birds,
that's enough food for them.
If they eat more, they'll explode!
[hopeful music playing]
What an idea you just gave me!
- What do you mean?
- I mean...
- Come, I will show you.
- What?
[hopeful music continues]
A Sparrow is a small bird.
A Turboprop is a small plane.
Small birds fly low,
so they eat less food.
Similarly, smaller planes fly
at lower altitudes,
so they consume lesser fuel!
Less fuel, means cheaper tickets, Rani!
We'll turn cargo planes
into passenger planes.
First time in India, Rani!
[Uncle] Even cheaper tickets?
Will you fly people for free now?
And this Tur-Tur-Turbapaap!
What is it?
Turboprop, uncle.
[Sam] A small plane.
Like the airplane version
of a hatchback car.
All big planes fly at 35000 feet.
These fly at half the altitude.
So they consume less fuel.
But a small plane would fit
fewer passengers, right?
Yes, but how many passengers
do other airlines require
to run at full capacity? 200.
We'll need only 70! That's it!
If our tickets cost half
the price of other airlines,
people will definitely come.
And all flights will soon...
Become full! Right!
That sounds great.
But how do we get these...
Turbo-pops?
The Turboprop company's planes
used to be passenger planes.
But when business went downhill,
they began to use them for cargo.
We'll turn them into
passenger planes again!
We'll offer Turboprop a joint venture.
Fifty percent partnership!
It's an offer they can't refuse!
Mr. Mhatre, a fifty percent partnership
is out of question.
We're already leading
in the small planes market.
No ma'am you are not.
Right now, all your passenger planes
are flying as cargo planes.
I'm saying we will turn them
back into passenger planes.
But sir, these small planes
can't fly such long distances.
One minute.
You know how during the winters,
small birds migrate over 20,000 miles?
- How do they do it?
- By making stops.
Exactly!
Our small planes will also
make pit stops.
So a plane from Vijaywada to Delhi
can halt at Bhopal and Nagpur. Right?
Short flights. Big connectivity!
And what if we don't get flyers?
Ma'am, India has the biggest
middle-class in the world.
16 Million people travel by train
per day.
And another 12 million by road.
For us to run full capacity,
out of these 28 Million people,
we need only two percent Ma'am.
Just two percent.
Mr. Mhatre, let's do it!
Thank you Ma'am,
Bro!
[Everyone cheering]
You owe me 800 rupees
for tea this month.
Come on, uncle!
We're talking about 80 million,
and you're whining about 800 bucks!
Put it on the tab!
Don't have 800 bucks in your pocket,
and you're talking of 80 million!
You need money to make money!
Shall we grab some vada-pav?
I'm craving it since morning!
You were going to do
accounts today, right?
- Is it done?
- Yeah.
Is everything okay?
Honestly, even if we made 200-300,
I'd be satisfied.
But we're making a thousand!
A thousand! In a week?
In a day!
All the girls from the college
across the road come to have cake...
And all the boys follow,
to woo them with cakes!
It's such a great location!
Whose idea was it?
Yeah, I'm sure you must have
tried to woo girls with cake too.
That's how you got the idea, right?
Mhatre!
Brother! Two vada-pavs,
and one tea, with extra sugar.
[Vada-pav seller] Ok.
Here you go.
[Bystander] Brother, a vada-pav please.
- No, I don't want it.
- What happened?
Tell me.
Go on.
Paresh is out of India for a month.
If we submit our papers
to the Ministry quickly,
we can get our planes to India
before he comes back.
If he's around, he'll surely
mess with our plans.
- You're right.
- I have prepared everything.
The security manual is ready,
I have an ok from Turboprop as well.
Then get the planes.
What's the problem?
Rani, we need to register the company.
If you could lend me
fifteen thousand rupees...
[serious music playing]
Rani, if the Turboprop deal
gets closed somehow...
This time the company
will definitely take off.
And in three months,
I can pay you back!
Take the money from him.
Its four and a half rupees.
Rani!
Rani listen. Rani!
[serious music continues]
Not fifteen...
Take twenty thousand.
You always dream so big,
petty talk doesn't suit you.
Feeling embarrassed for taking money
from your own wife?
[hopeful music playing]
I'll take that, sir.
Sorry.
Didn't I tell you?
There's no 'yours' or 'mine'.
All my cakes are yours.
And all your planes will be mine.
That was our deal, right?
Right.
Sorry.
[upbeat music playing]
Now go.
Go!
Yeah, break it. Break everything!
[music stops]
What are you staring at?
Show me the accounts!
Get up! Hey! Get up!
Sir...
Bloody pauper,
sleeping like he owns the place!
- Sorry, sir.
- Brother!
- What's up? Why are you shouting?
- Nothing...
Why are you still up?
- It's nothing, don't be silly-
- Bhavar, tell me!
- Is there a problem?
- Come with me...
It's a small issue. I'll manage it.
Bhavar, I've told you
so many times...
I don't care if you don't
give me good news,
but bad news -
tell me immediately!
Turboprop refused the
cargo aircraft deal today.
Someone has reserved them
for passenger flights.
But don't worry-
Who? Who did it?
I'm finding out...
- Call Deshmukh!
- Brother, it's 3 am!
So what? I'm awake, aren't I?
I don't care if he's asleep!
Go, call him!
[music intensifies]
One minute... One minute!
- Here it is, sir.
- What is it?
[Deshmukh] Sir, it's a joint venture between
Turboprop International
and VR Aviation Pvt. Ltd.
Registered in the name of Rani Divekar.
Who's that?
Vir Mhatre's wife.
[Deshmukh] Sir, you were out of India,
so I didn't bother you...
You're the only one who deals
with Turboprop Aviation in India,
I assumed it was just a dummy company
that you created for tax purposes.
Wow! He managed to outsmart
a man like me!
Don't worry, Mr. Paresh!
He won't be able to do anything.
Every Tom, Dick or Harry
can't run an airline!
And a man with sharp acumen like you...
[line disconnected tone beeping]
Okay, now what?
Let them fly!
[Paresh laughing]
How will we fly?
We still need an
investment of 32.5 million.
Can we cut costs anywhere else?
Vir!
How's it going?
Every guy on the street
knows about Rani Bakery!
Your Honeybun has become famous!
Mandar... What brings you here?
Guess what uncle,
my sister's marriage has been fixed!
All of you must come.
Hey Vir, we'll rag the groom together!
She thinks of you as her brother,
even more than me.
Come two days in advance.
Take charge of feeding the guests.
Vir... think practically.
How much can we cut costs?
This doesn't make sense.
You guys continue your work.
I'll hang around the corner.
You guys have made
all these colourful pastries...
Give me some samples!
Stop being a freeloader!
Fine, you can have some
since you travelled so far.
I've tried everything, man.
This is the minimum we need.
It looks impossible.
We shouldn't have rushed
into the deal with Turboprop--
What else could we have done?
Your father-in-law is right!
You give up even before trying!
All you can do is chant,
'impossible, impossible!'
Go to hell!
[somber music playing]
Hey Sam...
Don't mind him, okay?
It's okay, Uncle.
He's just stressed about the money.
But I know, he'll figure out something.
These three have invested
their entire lives' savings into this.
How will they get 32.5 million more?
Hey, if I had the money,
I'd give it to you.
Sir, how much is it?
Vir, normally I would directly
inform the Income Tax Department...
But I wanted to check with you first.
Look.
Rupees 1,50,000... 20,000...
1,00,000... 10,000...
Various amounts are being deposited
from Jarandeshwar into your account.
Since yesterday.
Another transaction just happened.
What's going on, Vir?
Sir, can I make a phone call?
Sure.
Vir! Did you get the money?
We've postponed Sayali's wedding a bit...
The boy is mad about her!
He'll wait.
Are you crazy, Mandar?
[Mandar] Speak to Uncle Sharad.
Vir! You got the money, right?
I've sent you 2,00,000.
Uncle... Where did you get
so much money from?
From the money-lender, of course!
I've signed off my land as collateral.
Don't you worry!
Why did you give your land
to that leech, Uncle!
Ever since we got train connectivity,
our land's value increased twenty-fold.
Thanks to whom?
You!
You've done so much
for our village,
and you expect us to
turn our backs on you?
No way, buddy!
[Mandar] One minute, speak to Uncle...
Vir, the crops failed this year,
only the chillies did well.
I'm sending you 500 rupees, son.
Did you get the money?
Why, Uncle?
Vir! Speak to Gauri.
Vir Uncle!
Yes, Gauri... tell me.
[Gauri] Vir uncle, I broke open my piggy bank.
When will you take me on a plane ride?
[Mandar] Day 3 of our Airplane fund!
Contribute what you can,
no amount is too small!
And irrespective,
please eat before you leave!
We've organised tea and snacks!
Rupees 20,000... 10,000... 31,000...
Not 31, 000, it's 3.1 million, dumbo!
Vir, you go get your planes.
We'll have Sayali's wedding party
on a plane then!
[Mandar] Up in the clouds.
Listen to me.
I can't accept this money.
Go to that loan shark right away
and get everyone's land back.
Or I'll come there myself.
Got it?
[Kaveri] Vir!
There's nothing you can do
If you're a stubborn man's son,
I'm his wife!
[Kaveri] I went to the lender yesterday
with everyone's papers.
He won't return the land
without six months' interest.
So don't think of all this now.
Go, do your job.
Son, the entire village is with you.
Your father is with you.
Remember what he said?
"Vir is a man of his word!"
[Kaveri] Now go make him proud!
Make him proud, son!
You will, won't you?
Yes, Ma.
That's it. Go, fly!
Go, fly!
Vir will make it happen!
Mr. Vir, Paresh controls
all the airstrips in India.
Where do you plan to land your planes?
Very much here, sir.
Here? This is it?
These airstrips were used
in the British era,
for postal deliveries
and diplomatic trips.
But Vir, look at the condition!
How do you plan to run an airline
with three old, out of use airstrips?
Not three, sir.
Five hundred airstrips.
- Five hundred?
- Yes.
Let them burn with envy
With a bang, I shall arrive
Kicking sand in your eyes
Speak to Ma.
What?
We're calling it Deccan Air.
Excellent!
If you clap with me
[music continues playing]
This loser's now on top
If someone gives you a push
give him a hard shove
If a passenger has a credit card,
they can book a ticket online
through your software.
But Mr. Bill Gates...
How many people in India
have a credit card?
But they have phones, right?
See, they'll call our call centre
and book their tickets.
And with the PNR number generated,
they can collect the ticket
from a bank or supermarket!
But Vir...
If Interworld made this software,
it would test it for six months at least.
But we can't afford that, man.
Are you sure this will work?
[Father-in-law] Yes,
of course it will work!
[baby crying]
Don't be nervous,
let's do this!
We want a tiny stall
next to the reservation counter.
Why would we send our passengers
to the competition, Mr. Mhatre?
Look, most of your trains
are always running full.
In fact, ten to fifteen thousand passengers
are always on waitlists.
They need to travel too.
We will only sell tickets to
passengers who are on the waitlist
who complain about the railways.
It's a win-win for the
passengers and the railways.
Sir, we can never be your competition.
All the best.
Congratulations!
You passed the medical exam.
You are fit.
You can leave. Next!
[music continues playing]
The player sets out of the house
With dreams of touching the sky
When he's on a high
everyone stands back
With iron wings
He soars in the sky
He might look innocent
but he's got nerves of steel
Deccan Air won't find pilots.
We offered double the salary.
All of them flocked here.
Fire all of them after a month.
Why?
People whose loyalties are for
sale can be bought by anyone.
Vir! Not one of our pilots turned up!
There's something fishy for sure.
Nothing to be surprised about.
Paresh is capable of anything.
And so are we!
[Vir] Retired Air Force officers.
[Uncle] They're retired!
How can these oldies
fly aeroplanes?
Uncle, the retirement age for
Air Force pilots is 57...
But for Civilian Pilots, it's 61!
They can fly for 4 more years!
[Vir] Captain Rajiv Manohar.
He co-ordinated everything.
If someone gives you a push
give him a hard shove
[music continues playing]
Hello. Investor Madam?
What brings you here?
I have a business proposal!
Oh. I have a business proposal too...
to mix business with pleasure...
Is this how you conduct
business with everyone?
Sorry.
Mr. Mhatre...
I'd like you to grant the contract
for Deccan Air's in- flight catering
to Rani Caterers.
But how would it be possible
to operate from one city?
We won't be operating from one city.
Rani Bakery is expanding its business.
Rani Bakery will have branches
in Mumbai, Vijayawada and Pune
which will be run by me,
Che's mother and my brother.
Projected monthly turnover, 1 million.
Which comes to 12 million a year.
Your cut - forty percent.
Sorry, your cut will be
forty percent, sir.
But Ms. Rani, you'll be treated
like any other vendor.
No special deals for you.
You won't get any
special discounts either.
Fair enough.
Confirmed deal?
Welcome to Deccan Air,
Rani Bakery!
Business is over?
Can we look into that proposal now?
[upbeat music playing]
Hey Vir!
Our plane's landing for
the first time today, right?
According to Vaastu Shastra, it should
be facing the west. Please tell Che!
Hey Uncle, there's no runway
towards the west.
Want him to land the plane
into a ditch?
I got this coconut from Begumpet market
with such difficulty...
I'll smash it on the wing
of the plane like...
Calm down!
We have to do it, it's tradition.
Hey Mhatre!
Is that ours?
- Yes it is.
- Uncle!
Our plane! There.
Why is he circling?
Begumpet tower, is there an issue?
- What is happening?
- What happened?
- Sam!
- Yes?
Vir!
- Hey, stop, stop!
- Something's happened, let me go see!
You're pregnant!
Unable to go around.
This is a fuel emergency, goddammit!
I repeat, turn back Deccan Air 582!
Why aren't they allowing us
to land, Captain?
There's something wrong.
Begumpet tower,
requesting reason for denial!
You're not cleared to land,
Deccan Air 582.
I'm out of fuel...
Why won't you let me land?
Mr. Paresh, this is too risky!
You said we were only
going to scare them off!
You are using Civil Aviation property!
If the plane crashes,
I'll be under enquiry!
- How dare you-
- Deshmukh...
Who got you this position
in the DGCA?
Brother, we're already
under a CBI enquiry.
We've scared them enough already!
We should stop.
[ATC operator] You're not cleared to land,
Deccan Air 582. I repeat...
[Vir] Why aren't they letting you land?
Che, this is Vir.
How much fuel is left?
[Che] Six minutes!
I can do one more landing.
Che, divert the plane to
the Air Force station,
Hakimpet Airfield,
Number 1733, E07831.
Switch to company frequency, now!
- [Vir] Go, go, go.
- [ATC Operator] Who the hell are you?
That's my plane, moron!
[ATC Operator] Hey,
wait! You can't do this.
Someone call the guards!
Security breach at gate number 1.
stop them
Che! You're out of fuel,
weight minimum!
Switch to endurance speed setting!
Don't teach me how
to fly a bloody plane!
My father had warned me...
Don't be friends with this rascal,
he'll get you killed someday!
If something goes wrong,
tell Preeti I love her.
Sure, I'll let that Brigadier's daughter
know as well!
Shut up!
Che! You better not die, buddy!
[intense music playing]
Come in, Che!
Che, come in Che!
Are you okay, Che?
Get some help!
Open the emergency hatch!
Stop! Get on your knees!
- We are ex-Air Force officers! Don't shoot.
- Help the pilots! Please help my pilots!
[beeping]
We are ex-Air Force officers!
There are two pilots inside!
Batch of '87!
Please help the pilots!
[somber music playing]
Vir!
- Che! Careful!
- Vir!
Get up!
Careful.
- Jai Hind sir!
- Sir!
Chaitanya, why didn't
you declare Mayday
to get landing permission
on Begumpet Civil Airport?
If we had declared Mayday,
they would seize all our planes
for six months.
Our airline launch is on the 25th August...
and that needs to happen, sir.
Yes?
Jai hind Sir!
The Airports Authority are calling.
They want an update to give the press.
Three years ago,
a Saudi Boeing had an emergency landing,
on this very airstrip.
- Chaitanya!
- Sir.
Do you know what we did then?
We investigated for terrorist links, sir.
And imposed a fine too...
50 million.
There have been multiple
security breaches today.
Along with the fine,
you could face ten years in jail.
Vir Jagannath Mhatre...
You've made a lot of enemies
before you've even taken off.
Well, I'm done with my investigation!
Report to the Airports Authority -
These three monkeys...
aren't terrorists.
But for landing at an Air Force Base
without permission...
They must pay a fine.
25,000 rupees.
Within three months of
the airline launch.
- Dismissed!
- Sir!
Let's go, Vir!
Vir...
But you never liked me, sir.
I still don't!
But what you're doing today
is much bigger than our egos.
Son, If I didn't punish
you during training,
I would've lost the respect
of my cadets.
And if I punish you today,
I would lose respect for myself.
A soldier never abandons
a fellow soldier in trouble.
You lived up to that ideal today,
Vir Jagannath Mhatre!
- You are a true leader.
- Thank you.
[patriotic music playing]
I don't smoke, sir...
And at your age,
neither should you.
Don't you dare
talk about my age, man.
Get out!
Mr. Mhatre, I'm really
sorry to have heard that
your plane crashed yesterday!
Sorry...
This aviation business isn't
everybody's cup of tea.
Look at Ratan! He still hasn't- -
Oh Lord! Why does every moron
keep telling me about Tata!
I'm no millionaire.
I have nothing to lose.
The public is behind me.
Public!
Today they're behind you,
tomorrow they'll be running after you.
That's exactly what I want, sir.
When the public runs after me,
who will buy your expensive tickets?
Now excuse me,
I have an airline to run, my friend!
See you.
No matter what we do...
This guy isn't going to stop.
Jayesh.
Hey, Jayesh!
Jaiwant, sir.
Yeah, that.
Have you heard of Vir Mhatre?
The man who's going to
sell cheap air tickets, right?
Yes. Will you buy a ticket?
How can I afford a plane ticket, sir?
After all, how cheap can it be?
One rupee, sir!
A flight ticket for one rupee?
10-15 seats go empty
in most flights.
The advance booking price
for these seats will be one rupee.
Reserving ten seats and claiming
a ticket price of one rupee...
Aren't you fooling the people?
Deccan Air has three planes currently.
Three planes, minimum six trips each.
200 people can travel daily
on a one rupee ticket, sir.
After the first ten seats
are booked for one rupee,
there will be some seats for 1500,
then some for 2500, and so on.
As the date of travel approaches,
the ticket prices will increase.
Still, even the most expensive
tickets on our flights
will be half the price of
other airlines' tickets.
On some short distance routes,
our tickets will be
as cheap as train tickets.
If it's really as cheap
as a train ticket...
Then I'll definitely take
my mother on a flight!
She's a sanitation worker, sir.
She's never even seen a plane!
Sir, if you inaugurate our flight,
your voters will see your commitment
to the common man's progress.
The common man who can
now dream of flying
with just one rupee in his pocket.
Those who clean public toilets
will now be seated next to us.
He's flying high on people's trust.
We have to break that trust.
Our Government has only one goal-
the progress of the common man.
Ever since I joined politics,
it was my dream
to see common people fly
on aeroplanes.
It's with great pride today,
that I announce the launch of Deccan Air!
[people clapping and cheering]
Master would have been
so proud today!
Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls, good morning.
You're welcome onboard
Deccan Air's maiden flight.
We are now ready for departure,
enjoy our services, thank you.
Inserting the metal tip
into the buckle...
Two forward and two rear...
Removal of the life-jacket
without crew authorization.
[inspirational music playing]
Deccan Air 582,
ready for departure.
Line up and clear for take off.
Wind Calm.
[inspirational music continues]
Stop. Stop! Fire!
Please be seated. Stay calm.
Please be seated.
Stay calm!
Ok... Just calm down!
Have everybody seated! Just stay calm!
There is smoke in engine one.
Please call captain to open the door.
Stay calm!
Open the door, captain!
What the hell is happening?
How can you do that?
Captain, smoke!
Captain, smoke in the engine!
Captain, smoke abort!
Captain! Captain abort! Captain!
Abort! Cap...
Captain!
Reject take off power.
Lever idle.
Applying maximum brakes!
Deccan Air 582 to Mumbai Tower!
Mayday! Mayday! Engine smoke...
Evacuate... Evacuate...
Evacuate.
[people screaming]
- Come here sir. Please come.
- This is very wrong.
Come this way!
Move everybody out now.
Careful. Take sir with you.
- Let's go sir.
- Sir, please hear me out!
Sir it's a small little glitch,
I'll fix it in half an hour! Please!
Small glitch?
Mr. Mhatre, I nearly lost my life!
Deccan Air is a total failure!
- Please don't say that, sir...
- Move!
Sir please listen to me...
Sir please, hear me out!
Sir! Sir!
- [Reporters] Guys, guys, guys!
- [Reporters] Sir! Sir!
We want answers!
Mr. Vir Mhatre, how did the
aircraft engine catch fire?
There was no fire,
just excess oil spillage.
There was no danger
to the passengers.
You put Minister Parekh's life
in danger...
Do you have any links
to the opposition party?
What nonsense!
Stop making such wild claims!
It was his first brush with death
on your flight, sir!
How could you let this happen?
[voices fade]
[slow music playing]
[Rani groans]
Rani?
Vir!
[slow music continues]
Don't come.
I will handle it.
Let's go.
Come on.
[Reporters] How could you do that, sir?
How can you leave
without answering us?
Look, we did proper safety checks.
We got our air-worthiness certificate
through the proper channels.
Low-cost aviation doesn't mean that
we'll compromise passenger safety.
We've followed every single rule...
Our country is already struggling
with so many problems...
Do we really need this luxury?
It's this luxury barrier in aviation
that has to be broken!
Just like food, water, electricity
and medical facilities,
low-cost aviation is crucial
to our progress as a nation!
This is my field,
this is where I can make a difference!
[Reporters clamouring]
[inaudible dialogue]
[Reporter] People are not about to get into
one of these flights in a hurry,
That's the death of Deccan Air,
even before it's born.
[Reporter 2] People have lost all
faith in Deccan Air.
This was their first flight,
and will likely be their last too.
[slow music playing]
[Rani] Master-ji...
Damn it.
- Che!
- What?
Oil spillage!
Such a basic mistake?
- You did the last fuel check, Vir!
- What?
Captain Manohar told me
that you're doing it...
But he told me you're doing it!
I needed the money.
I'm under a lot of debt.
More than me?
Money, power...
They have it all.
The only weapon we have...
is the strength to say no.
I trusted you, Captain.
That's it?
Won't we throw him out?
Vir, we should fire him!
He's my father's age.
You can go, Captain.
Captain Manohar, was Deccan Air
lax about safety protocols?
Where did Deccan Air go wrong?
Was Deccan Air negligent, Captain?
No, sir.
But given what happened on
the flight, it seems...
Sir, it was my fault.
It was due to my negligence
that excessive fueling happened.
That's what created all the smoke.
Captain Manohar,
what you're saying
could land you in jail.
Please give your statement
without any fear or pressure...
Sir, this is my statement.
Deccan Air is not responsible.
And it's evident who in this room
is scared, and of whom.
What are you hinting at?
- Talk clearly...
- Okay, fine!
He's accepted his mistake.
Please sign on your statement.
File the report as pilot's negligence.
Pilot is grounded for twelve months.
And Deccan Air is cleared of all charges!
Deccan Air is clear to fly.
- All the best, Vir.
- Thank you.
[Reporter] The DGCA has cleared Deccan Air,
but the public still seem to be sceptical.
People have lost
all faith in Deccan Air.
A big question mark hangs
on Deccan Air's future.
Amidst all these safety concerns,
Deccan Air has crashed before take off.
The question arises:
was the DGCA bribed to brush it off?
[Radio] For all its claims of selling
tickets for one rupee,
Deccan Air may not be able
to sell even one ticket now.
How can ordinary folks like us fly?
These are rich people's hobbies!
It's all a money-making scam!
What complete idiots!
He's destroyed people's trust in us.
[Reporter] The end is near for Deccan Air.
People's faith in Deccan Air
has been shattered.
We clarified so many times!
We gave interviews, statements...
Yeah.
We cleared the enquiry, and still...
[phone ringing]
Not a single headline
is in our favour!
Hello?
Sir!
We'll be there, sir.
Who? What?
The founder of India's biggest airline,
Jaz Airways - Mr. Paresh Goswami
joins us for a special interview,
tomorrow night at 9 pm!
Why don't you ever
charge your phone?
Listen.
I got a call from Walia's office.
He wants to buy Deccan Air.
He's offering 150 million.
You refused, right?
Vir, let's at least meet him once.
I'm not interested.
Vir...
The train is in the evening.
I'll take your leave.
Why? At least stay the night?
No, I just came to see the baby...
Vir...
Sayali's to-be in-laws were
asking about the wedding date...
No pressure!
Just think and let me know...
I'll take care of the rest.
Alright then.
[baby fussing]
Vir...
Are you sure you
want to say no to Walia?
I mean, let's discuss it once?
Didn't I tell you?
I don't want to do
any business with them.
You guys sit, I'll serve the food.
Vir just...
How can you decide alone?
You call this a partnership?
Does only your opinion count?
Che.
We're on the verge of losing everything!
Ever since I left the Air Force,
my father hasn't spoken to me!
Sam faces taunts daily
from his father-in-law!
Stop it Che.
At least think of
your own daughter!
You want her to grow up
paying your debts?
- What are you saying?
- Go on! Hit me, bugger!
How do you sleep at night?
1100 people have invested
their life's savings on your dream!
- And you can't accept a good offer...
- Che, stop it.
- Only because of your ego!
- It's not my ego!
It's my belief!
We can do it.
Why do you think Walia
is giving us such a big offer?
Because he knows that
if Deccan Air takes off,
it will change India forever.
He wants to buy us
so he can make sure
that the skies remain out of
the common man's reach!
Che, why did we
quit the Air Force?
What did we set out to do?
We are so close...
If we take their
150 million today,
900 million Indians
will never be able to fly!
[suspenseful music playing]
Che!
[baby crying]
[suspenseful music continues]
[Vir sniffles]
I didn't think of our family...
You didn't mix rat poison
in the food, did you?
I would have...
If you had accepted the offer.
[sad music playing]
Vir!
This is a radio station.
Goswami is speaking to every
TV news channel out there...
The people I want to reach
will hear me on the radio.
People tune into FM stations
more these days...
I'll speak to some friends
who work there...
We'll fix some interviews there too.
- Thank you.
- Okay. Ready?
3, 2, 1... Go!
Vir Mhatre... Why Deccan Air?
People like us have always
been told that we cannot fly.
That no matter how hard we try,
we can never touch the skies.
But we want the sky to be in
the common man's grasp.
That's why, Deccan Air.
In order to move ahead,
at times we must walk,
at times we must run,
and at times, we must fly.
Which is why our airline will
bring air connectivity to small cities.
So that people from smaller
cities and towns can also progress.
Tell me, should success only be
the monopoly of the rich?
A century ago, they said
we didn't need electricity...
Fifty years ago,
we didn't need cars!
And now, they say
we don't need to fly. Why?
Because our lives are
worth nothing to them.
Our time is worth nothing.
We crawl on the earth
like insects to survive
and they fly in the skies
just for pleasure.
Sir, there's one topic
that's on everyone's minds.
Low-cost aviation.
What are your thoughts on this?
When you're flying at
an altitude of thirty thousand feet,
at a speed of thousand km per hour,
in a box made of aluminium...
What's your top priority?
- Safety.
- Exactly!
And to ensure this safety,
you require testing and checking
equipment, you need training.
And all of this costs money.
If you sell tickets this cheap,
how can you provide all this?
To be honest, I don't just feel
worried for their passengers,
I feel scared for them.
They aren't scared for us,
They are scared of us.
If the people who drive their cars,
cook their food and clean their homes
sit side-by-side with them today,
tomorrow they might even
rise above them!
They're talking about safety?
Then go ask them this:
Business class tickets are thrice
as expensive as economy.
So are Business class passengers
guaranteed thrice the level of safety?
Cheap tickets doesn't mean that
we compromise on safety.
Sir, Deccan Air has passed
every standard safety test
that their airline has passed.
Brother and sisters,
don't think twice!
Make one phone call,
and book your Deccan Air ticket!
Show your PNR number,
and collect your ticket
from your nearest post office
or petrol pump!
Come quick, come now!
Take a flight through the clouds!
If I may be honest with you...
In these current times,
bringing low-cost aviation to India
is a huge risk!
It's akin to mass murder!
And we've already seen
how they've lowered the standards
of the aviation industry.
It's a substandard product.
Retired pilots...
Our pilots have flown fighter jets
for the Indian Air force.
You couldn't possibly
be in safer hands!
What motivates you to do this?
Is it money?
If making money was my goal,
I'd have done anything else.
Run a business,
bought a plane for myself.
I could just chill at home
and enjoy life.
My wife's bakery business
is doing very well.
And you're asking me
why I'm doing all this?
I don't just want to break
the cost barrier for people,
I want to break
the goddamn caste barrier too!
That's the reason our tickets
cost as low as one rupee.
Not because of poor quality.
Are your lives worth
only one rupee?
How is safety possible
at this cost?
I'll do one final safety test
for everyone to see.
The three people who
are most precious to me
will travel on Deccan Air's
first flight...
My mother,
my wife Rani,
and my eight day-old
daughter, Amu.
To trust such a man
with running an airline
is like handing a gun
to a madman.
He must be stopped.
My God!
He says it so convincingly that
even I have started believing him!
- Vir!
Che and I have been trying
to call you for so long!
My phone's battery is down
and so is mine.
You haven't slept for three days.
Let's go home, buddy.
What if that rascal tries
to sabotage us again?
We'll have to guard
our aircraft on our own.
[inspirational music playing]
I've sent my boys to guard the
Vijaywada and Pune hangars too.
You think Paresh is the
only one with manpower?
We never abandon a fellow soldier.
Go home and sleep.
Let me see who has
the guts to step in over here.
Boys!
Yes, sir!
[inspirational music continues playing]
Take care of the Wing Tip clearance.
All in position at Bay 63.
[Announcer] All passengers
travelling to Pune via flight DA 581,
please proceed to Gate Number 2
for boarding.
I repeat, all passengers traveling
to Pune via flight DA 581,
please proceed to Gate Number 2
for boarding.
- Sir! Sir!
- Sir, look at this.
Come on.
Are we ready for boarding?
- Yes, sir.
- Perfect.
Yeah? Are the luggage
tractors in position?
- Welcome, captain.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
[inspirational music continues playing]
No, no, no...
Ma'am your boarding pass.
Thank you.
Might as well have
taken the bus to Pune.
They've parked our plane
in such a remote corner.
No matter what they do,
we'll fly.
[music picks up]
People will come, right?
Come on. Get inside.
[Announcer] This is the last and
final boarding call for passengers
travelling from Mumbai to Pune
on Flight DA 581.
I repeat.
Smile. Keep a smile.
Come on, smile everyone!
After the colossal failure
of Deccan Air's launch,
will people even get on to
their flights?
This idiot's phone
is always switched off!
[Reporter] People would reject
such an unsafe airline
and yes, it does look like
the end for Deccan Air.
Captain, this flight
has been cancelled.
[somber music playing]
What happened?
I couldn't win the people's trust.
[sad music playing]
Let's go.
How can a common man
ever fly on a plane!
It's all a money- making scam!
Running an airline
is for big shots.
Go back to your village
and ride a bullock cart!
[Paresh] Trusting such a man
to run an airline
is like handing a gun
to a madman.
Are your lives worth
only one rupee?
[Kaveri] The entire village has
put their faith in you.
Don't let them lose!
You'll win!
You'll win, son...
I know you will!
[Prakash] He only noticed you for ten minutes...
And all your dreams of
flying in the sky
went crashing down
into the sewer.
[sad music continues]
Vir! Vir!
I'm sorry man!
Vir, I'm sorry man,
I'm really sorry!
I'm such a bloody idiot!
I don't know what I did!
- Sorry man!
- Why are you saying sorry?
No man, it's my fault!
I screwed up!
The Mumbai booking software
had some bug
which cancelled all our bookings
It reversed--
One second,
what are you saying?
People had booked tickets
for our Mumbai flight...
But our software had some bug
which cancelled all the bookings
from our end!
Vir... I'm sorry!
I am really sorry.
Vir! Vir!
Vir!
[suspenseful music playing]
The entire flight was full!
Tickets have been
booked in thousands!
[Sam] The entire flight was full!
[uplifting music playing]
[Sam] Only the Mumbai software
had a bug...
All our other flights are full!
Pune, Vijayawada...
all flights are full!
All Deccan Air flights for
the next three days are full!
[Sam] The public trusts us!
The public trusts us!
We have won!
We won, Vir! We won!
Oh winds,
Glance at the homeless
Who took their stake
in the hamlet of aether!
Someone go write
On the tablet of time
That we gave wings
To cracked feet
For one ambition
We rose from ashes
To quench our limitless thirst
[Announcer] Ladies and Gentlemen, this
is to announce that Flight No - DA589
from Vijaywada to Mumbai
has just arrived.
We will pass one day
but this story shall live on
We will pass
But our spirit will live on
Look at us, O birds
Look at us, O clouds
Vir!
[song continues playing]
Vir, I just flew on a plane!
It was amazing.
I flew with my own money.
Well done, son!
Vir!
Look at this.
We all flew here.
Look!
Time had to bow down
To sheer courage
He who fights with destiny
Is known as a braveheart
What was deemed impossible
You turned it into reality
You filled the empty sky
with fireflies
My child...
You finally did it.
[Kaveri weeping]
You did it...
[Kaveri] If Vir says he'll make
the villagers fly on a plane,
he'll do it for sure!
[music continues playing]
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Paresh!
- Hello!
- [Paresh] Congratulations, Mr. Vir Mhatre!
I was waiting for your call.
Fantastic!
I have a business proposal for you.
I'll ask my secretary
to fix an appointment.
Who are you to offer me
a business proposal?
- What?
- Whether I live or die,
no matter what you do,
no matter how much
power you wield,
you can't stop us anymore.
The common man has
spread his wings today.
Now he'll keep flying higher.
Remember that.
The sky isn't your Dad's property.
Now cut the call, moron.
Hang up!
[upbeat music playing]
Run and soar
This rocky path has caved
to the might of the brave
He who walks carefree
flaunting his battle scars
This maverick shall go far
Hello.
What do you do?
I run a barbershop.
And you?
I'm a businessman,
just like you!
He's the King of the Silk trade!
He's the one who invested
3.1 million in our airline!
He's a big man!
There are no big or small men...
These barriers have been broken,
thanks to that crazy man!
I told you, didn't I?
Bye!
What do you want, old woman!
Ah! So you want to fly
on a one rupee ticket!
Forget the plane,
the cupcake was so good!
I'll buy another ticket
just to have it again!
Heard that, honeybun?
Hey, why are you crying!
- Whose idea was it?
- It was hers.
Mr. Parekh! How are you, sir?
How have you been!
Goswami! What were you thinking?
That I won't find out
that you sabotaged
the plane I was in?
- Me?
- I could've died.
- No sir, it's a misunderstanding!
- Get out.
One minute...
- Sir this is sheer misunderstanding...
- Out!
Let me explain!
He's not married yet!
Oh, my!
Vir, did she fly us here?
Yes, how does that feel?